{
	"Questions": [
	  {
		"question": "What is the main function of the respiratory system?",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Digestion",
		  "b) Transportation of oxygen",
		  "c) Regulation of body temperature",
		  "d) Movement of muscles"
		],
		"answer": "b) Transportation of oxygen"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Which organ is responsible for the exchange of oxygen and carbon dioxide in the respiratory system?",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Lungs",
		  "b) Liver",
		  "c) Stomach",
		  "d) Kidneys"
		],
		"answer": "a) Lungs"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What muscle helps in the process of breathing by contracting and relaxing?",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Biceps",
		  "b) Quadriceps",
		  "c) Diaphragm",
		  "d) Abdominals"
		],
		"answer": "c) Diaphragm"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Air enters the body through which of the following structures?",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Trachea",
		  "b) Esophagus",
		  "c) Urethra",
		  "d) Rectum"
		],
		"answer": "a) Trachea"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Which part of the respiratory system is responsible for warming and moistening the air we breathe?",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Bronchi",
		  "b) Lungs",
		  "c) Nasal cavity",
		  "d) Pharynx"
		],
		"answer": "c) Nasal cavity"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "The exchange of gases (oxygen and carbon dioxide) in the lungs occurs in the:",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Alveoli",
		  "b) Bronchioles",
		  "c) Trachea",
		  "d) Bronchi"
		],
		"answer": "a) Alveoli"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Which of the following is NOT a common respiratory disorder?",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Asthma",
		  "b) Bronchitis",
		  "c) Malaria",
		  "d) Pneumonia"
		],
		"answer": "c) Malaria"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What are tiny hair-like structures in the respiratory tract that help to trap and remove dust particles and pathogens?",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Alveoli",
		  "b) Villi",
		  "c) Cilia",
		  "d) Alveolus"
		],
		"answer": "c) Cilia"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What is the harmful effect of smoking on the respiratory system?",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Increases lung capacity",
		  "b) Reduces the risk of lung cancer",
		  "c) Damages the cilia in the airways",
		  "d) Improves oxygen intake"
		],
		"answer": "c) Damages the cilia in the airways"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "During physical activity, the respiratory rate:",
		"choices": [
		  "a) Decreases",
		  "b) Remains constant",
		  "c) Increases",
		  "d) Stops"
		],
		"answer": "c) Increases"
	  }
	]
  }
  
